MATT BOEGNER

DATA ENGINEER



Matt.Boegner@Gmail.com



804-651-8177

mattboegner.com





OVERVIEW

Data Engineer with varied experience in cloud services and a demonstrated ability to guide teams through complexity while streamlining large-scale technical implementations.

Certifications



amazon AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, 2017



CompTIA Network+, 2016 CompTIA Security+, 2016

Skills & Expertise

AWS (Redshift, Kinesis/Firehose, S3, DynamoDB, EMR, SQS) **Snowflake Computing** Looker | Matillion ETL Agile Methodology

Google Cloud Platform (BigQuery, Firebase) SQL | PostgreSQL | MySQL Python | Git | Terraform **Data Warehousing**

Professional Experience

Lead Data Engineer | March 2018 - Present

Data Engineer | June 2017 - March 2018

- · Build robust data infrastructure for a startup travel company, integrating sources such as website, mobile app, and marketing data streams
- Develop an easily accessible platform for analytics and data science applications, relied on for most day-to-day operational decision-making

Engineering Spotlight



Established change management and testing processes for OLTP databases, data warehouse, and reporting systems to improve service reliability

Architecture Spotlight

- Serving as the company's primary data architect, refactoring databases to align with a microservices architecture and increasing the speed of feature
- Modeled and implemented a multi-team effort to overhaul the monolithic eCommerce application database

Data Science Spotlight

Collaborated with data analysts to create self-service BI dashboards, capturing key growth metrics, sessionization of user behavior, and custom A/B testing and experimentation frameworks

Consultant, ETL Developer | 2014-2016



UPSIDE

- Developed custom ETL tools for a large-scale data warehouse implementation for a manufacturing client
- Created web-based reports to inform business decisions with near real-time manufacturing data
- Streamlined cross-functional communication, proposed and rolled out Slack platform to all ~70 project members

Education



B.S. in Systems Engineering, Minor: Engineering Business

- President International Council on Systems Engineering at U.Va. (INCOSE)
- Founder of Zero-Waste Athletics, a multi-year sustainability initiative with over 17,500 total attendees

Projects & Interests

mattboegner.com Personal and professional website with tech, travel, and policy commentary Estonian e-Resident | Location-independent access to EU company formation and banking services